### Contact

375 Alaska st +553493334088 (Mobile) matheuskaze@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/matheusgcruz (LinkedIn) github.com/MatheusGCruz (Personal)

## Top Skills

Software Design

**SOAP** 

SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS)

## Languages

Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Japanese (Elementary)
Spanish (Professional Working)

### Certifications

Redis Essential Training

Registro CREA

Scrum Foundations Professional Certificate (SFPC) - (English)

Learning npm: A Package Manager

Developing Your Professional Image in a New Job

# Matheus Goncalves da Cruz

Senior Software Analyst || FullStack Developer || JAVA, C#, .Net, SQL, MongoDb

Uberlândia, Minas Gerais, Brazil

# Summary

I'm a mechatronics engineer, and graduated from the Federal University of Uberlandia.

Since 2016 I have worked in software development and systems management and support.

I have a very support focused profile. I learn a vast amount of programming languages, finding and fixing a large amount of bugs and errors, looking for the best customer experience.

I have a fast pace of learning, with a good adaptability, which makes me more agile to fix errors and problems in currently deployed applications, without worrying much about the software primary language.

I'm experienced a vast amount of computer languages, which varies from low level ones, like Assembly or C, to Back-end high level, such as C#, JAVA, VB, Front-end HTML, CSS, and even relational and non-relational databases, such as MSSQL, MySQL and MongoDB.

Most impacted systems and errors:

- Repair of a monolithic application, designed on VB.NET: The application was a monolithic system, and it had a rare error on a line ~4000. Everyone that looked on the code saw that the line 4000 was correct, but the error persisted. After a deep analisis, I found an incorrectly designed part, in line ~1500, and fixed it. This solved the error on line 4000.
- Support on a highly critical SSIS system: I was assigned as a "foster parent" on a high demanding, critical operation on a SSIS framework (didn't know, at the time, the complexity and the critical impact of this process). Never worked on a SSIS before (never even knew about it). In the first week, I managed to find my way into the code. In a matter of a month, I began to optimize this code. After a couple of months, I knew so much of this system, that I didn't even need to be in front of a computer to fix the issues.

# Experience

Arpia Tecnologia Senior Software Developer October 2024 - Present (5 months)

Uberlândia, Minas Gerais, Brazil

Primary type of the system: SaaS - Financial Institution

Systems running on Premises, with backend on C# -VB.NET - ASP.NET

**Primary Roles** 

Support and optimization of client's tools and applications

Programming languages and Frameworks:

Database modeling in relational databases (MSSQL, SyBase)

Backend languages: C#, VB, dotNet

Gitlab source version controller

Automated deploy Jenkins

Code quality assurance SonarQube

#### DISYS

Senior System Analyst January 2022 - November 2024 (2 years 11 months)

Primary type of the system: SaaS

System running on an Azure cloud service, using Azure for git control, CI/CD,

and Kubernetes hosting.

This system is on a Microservice architeture, running REST services on a

Springboot framework

Primary roles:

Support to applications and systems

Development of Fullstack projects

Application Maintenance and Optimization

Support to onsite representatives

Programming languages and Frameworks:

Databases - Sql Server, Cosmos

Web Applications - C#/Java as back, HTML/CSS/AngularJS/React as Front

System management applications in C#

Cloud applications in JAVA hosted on Azure servers

Algar Tech System Analyst May 2020 - January 2022 (1 year 9 months) Uberlândia, Minas Gerais

Primary type of the system: various

The systems covers a wide range of frameworks, but the most used ones was: SSIS - system responsible for the data processing on a daily basis JAVA/Springboot - Various systems using the spring framework, and with sensedia as API endpoint controller

Primary roles:

Support to applications and systems

Development of Fullstack projects

Application Maintenance and Optimization

Programming languages and Frameworks:

SSIS - Sql Server Integration Services

Web Applications - C#/VB as back, HTML/CSS/AngularJS as Front

System management applications in C#

Cloud applications in JAVA hosted on AWS servers

Sankhya Gestão de Negócios Software Developer January 2020 - May 2020 (5 months)

Uberlândia e Região, Brasil

Primary type of the system: ERP ERP system, using a custom framework

**Primary Roles:** 

Fullstack applications developer

Programming languages and Frameworks:

JAVA - backend component
HTML, CSS, NodeJS - Frontend Components
MSSQL, MySQL - database components
GitLab - Source code version control
Proprietary framework - SankhyaCode

Unica

Systems Analyst - Allocated January 2019 - November 2019 (11 months) Uberlândia e Região, Brasil

Primary type of the system: SaaS - Fintech

Systems running onPremises, with backend on JAVA/Spring and JAVA/tomcat(without frameworks). Majority of APIs on a SOAP protocol.

**Primary Roles** 

Support and optimization of client's tools and applications

Programming languages and Frameworks:

Database modeling in relational databases (MSSQL, MySQL, PostgresSQL, Oracle)

Backend languages Java (8 and Spring), C#, VB, dotNet Frontend languages HTML, CSS, AngularJS, jQuery Gitlab source version controller Automated deploy Jenkins Code quality assurance SonarQube

Arpia Tecnologia System Analyst May 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 7 months) Uberlândia Area, Brazil

Primary type of the system: SaaS - Fintech

Systems running onPremises, with backend on JAVA/Spring and JAVA/
tomcat(without frameworks). Majority of APIs on a SOAP protocol.

**Primary Roles** 

Comercial Tools development and support Support and optimization of client's tools and applications Support of legacy applications (JAVA and VB)

Programming languages and Frameworks:

Database modeling in relational databases (MSSQL, MySQL, PostgresSQL, Oracle)

Backend languages Java (8 and Spring), C#, VB, dotNet Frontend languages HTML, CSS, AngularJS, jQuery Gitlab source version controller Automated deploy Jenkins
Code quality assurance SonarQube

FMC Brasil Debt Collector August 2016 - March 2017 (8 months) Uberlândia, MG, Brasil

Primary Roles:

Telecharge of bankary debts Customer debts negotiation

Universidade Federal de Uberlândia Intern January 2015 - March 2015 (3 months) Uberlândia - MG

**Primary Roles:** 

Maintenance and organization of the Industrial Automation laboratory on the Mechanical Engineering Faculty of the Federal University of Uberlandia Students helper

Programming languages:

Ladder

## Education

Universidade Federal de Uberlândia

Mechatronics Engineering, Mechatronics, Robotics, Control and automation · (2007 - 2015)